Cailyn Hansen

Be Bold, Take Risks, Make Change

cailyn_hansen@brown.edu http://cailynhansen.com linkedin.com/in/cailynhansen +1 (218) 390-2919

Software engineer exploring the intersection of social justice and technology. Two and a half years of experience in each of: development of full-stack web applications; devops and system administration on Linux; and various programming tools. Solid background in database design, data science, and internet protocols.

Education

Brown University | Computer Science, B.A. and Ethnic Studies, B.A.

Sept. 2015 - May 2019

- Select Courses: Design and Implementation of Algorithms; Logic for Systems; Theory of Computation
- Computer Science GPA: 3.63

University of Minnesota-Duluth | *Additional Coursework – Dual Enrollment*

Sept. 2013 – May 2015

- Select Courses: Honors Computer Science 1, 2; Computer Science Theory; Linear Algebra; Combinatorics
- Overall GPA: 3.96

Experience

Software Engineer Intern | Facebook

May 2018 - Aug. 2018 (Summer 2018)

- Architect and implement configurable multi-channel notifications infrastructure for internal tool
- Restructure testing framework resulting in 11% performance boost across team test suite
- Implement new feature for trans and non-binary users with estimated 55,000 adopting users

Software Developer | Center for Digital Scholarship, Brown University Feb. 2017 – Present (Summer 2017)

- Maintain and update existing faculty web application and database projects
- Develop new digital projects through software architecture and data modeling services
- Manage development and production environments on DigitalOcean, Amazon EC2, and local machines

Software Engineer | Mapping Violence Project, Brown University

Apr. 2016 – June 2017 (Summer 2016)

- Lead team in the design and development of custom data collection and visualization applications
- Perform system administration on Linux servers and test and deploy software using Docker containers
- Communicate technology specifications and progress updates to non-technical team members

Select Projects

Database of Indigenous Slavery in the Americas | http://bit.ly/disa-github

Feb. 2017 – Present

- Create, iterate, and explain data models for representing unstructured data about slavery
- Develop application with stack consisting of Polymer, Node.is, Hapi.is, Google OAuth, and MongoDB
- Consider possible uses of web semantic technologies, linked open data, and domain-specific ontologies

Mapping Violence Applications | http://mappingviolence.org

Apr. 2016 – Aug. 2017

- Streamline data collection by building custom MVC web application using Apache Tomcat and jQuery
- Use MongoDB to develop storage solution and manage accounts with Google OAuth and Identity APIs
- Expose data via REST-like JSON API with SparkJava and use API with Leaflet.js to create visualizations
- Design and implement custom date format to handle ambiguity and imprecision in archival research

Database | Intro to Systems

Dec. 2016

- Implement in C a multi-threaded database server with both UDP and TCP connections
- Use POSIX Threads to enable concurrent client connections and mutexes to perform fine-graining locking for safe access; and properly handle system signals for clean disconnect

Leadership Experience

President | Undergraduate Parliament, Alpha Delta Phi Society

Mar. 2018 – Present

- Advise chapter presidents, chair monthly meetings, organize events, and liaison with national officers
- Undergraduate Teaching Assistant | Computer Science, Brown University

Nov. 2016 – May 2017

- Hold TA hours and answer questions on Piazza to facilitate student comprehension and learning

Interests

Spontaneous Road Trips, Recipe-less Cooking & Baking, Late Night Conversations, Digital Humanities